Curt Stern Papers 1907-1981 Mss.Ms.Coll.5
American Philosophical Society
- Correspondence, 1907-1981 (Box 1-43)
  - Principles of Human Genetics, 1942-1983; 5 boxes (Box 21-25)
    - Principles of Human Genetics - Chapter 13, 1956-1968; 3 folders (Box 22)
      - Folder 1, 1961-1964; 7 items (Box 22)
      - Folder 2, 1962-1968; 12 items (Box 22)
      - Folder 3, 1956; 2 items (Box 22)
    - Principles of Human Genetics - Chapter 14, 1956; 1 item (Box 22)
    - Principles of Human Genetics - Chapter 15, 1958-1970; 2 folders (Box 22)
      - Folder 1, 1968-1970; 6 items (Box 22)
      - Folder 2, 1958; 2 items (Box 22)
    - Principles of Human Genetics - Chapter 16, 1958-1969; 3 folders (Box 22)
      - Folder 1, 1964 (ca); 2 items (Box 22)
      - Folder 2, 1968-1969; 9 items (Box 22)
      - Folder 3, 1958; 4 items (Box 22)
    - Principles of Human Genetics - Chapter 17, 1958-1971; 8 folders (Box 22)
      - Folder 1, 1960-1967; 8 items (Box 22)
      - Folder 2, 1965-1970; 8 items (Box 22)
      - Folder 3, 1969-1971; 5 items (Box 22)
      - Folder 4, 1958-1962; 8 items (Box 22)
      - Folder 5, 1961-1969; 7 items (Box 22)
      - Folder 6, 1962-1960; 4 items (Box 22)
      - Folder 7, 1961-1968; 13 items (Box 22)
      - Folder 8, 1958; 2 items (Box 22)
    - Principles of Human Genetics - Chapter 18, 1957-1967; 3 folders (Box 22)
      - Folder 1, 1960-1967; 4 items (Box 22)
      - Folder 2, 1967; 3 items (Box 22)
      - Folder 3, 1957-1958; 4 items (Box 22)
    - Principles of Human Genetics - Chapter 19, 1961-1971; 2 folders (Box 22)
      - Folder 1, 1968; 2 items (Box 22)
      - Folder 2, 1961-1971; 3 items (Box 22)
    - Principles of Human Genetics - Chapter 20, 1957-1970; 5 folders (Box 23)
      - Folder 1, 1960-1968; 8 items (Box 23)
      - Folder 2, 1960-1969; 14 items (Box 23)
      - Folder 3, 1968-1970; 2 items (Box 23)
      - Folder 4, 1966-1967; 3 items (Box 23)
      - Folder 5, 1957-1960; 3 items (Box 23)
    - Principles of Human Genetics - Chapter 21, 1959-1983; 6 folders (Box 23)
      - Folder 1, 1960-1968; 4 items (Box 23)
      - Folder 2, 1959-1983; 20 items (Box 23)
      - Folder 3, 1968; 3 items (Box 23)
      - Folder 4, 1961-1964; 7 items (Box 23)
      - Folder 5, 1960; 1 item (Box 23)
      - Folder 6, 1970-1974; 5 items (Box 23)
    - Principles of Human Genetics - Chapter 22, 1967-1972; 3 items (Box 23)
    - Principles of Human Genetics - Chapter 23, 1964-1970; 5 items (Box 23)
    - Principles of Human Genetics - Chapter 24, 1964-1973; 4 folders (Box 23)
      - Folder 1, 1971; 3 items (Box 23)
      - Folder 2, 1971; 4 items (Box 23)
      - Folder 3, 1964-1968; 7 items (Box 23)
      - Folder 4, 1970-1973; 7 items (Box 23)
    - Principles of Human Genetics - Chapter 25, 1962; 3 items (Box 23)
    - Principles of Human Genetics - Chapter 26, 1948-1968; 2 folders (Box 23)
      - Folder 1, 1948-1951; 2 items (Box 23)
      - Folder 2, 1965-1968; 7 items (Box 23)
    - Principles of Human Genetics - Chapter 27, 1963-1973; 6 folders (Box 23)
      - Folder 1, 1965; 7 items (Box 23)
      - Folder 2, 1967-1969; 9 items (Box 23)
      - Folder 3, 1969-1970; 9 items (Box 23)
      - Folder 4, 1969-1970; 7 items (Box 23)
      - Folder 5, 1963-1972; 7 items (Box 23)
      - Folder 6, 1971-1973; 10 items (Box 23)
    - Principles of Human Genetics - Chapter 28, 1964-1971; 7 folders (Box 24)
      - Folder 1, 1970 (ca); 2 items (Box 24)
      - Folder 2, 1970 (ca); 1 item (Box 24)
      - Folder 3, 1969; 2 items (Box 24)
      - Folder 4, 1964; 4 items (Box 24)
      - Folder 5, 1968-1969; 3 items (Box 24)
      - Folder 6, 1966-1971; 8 items (Box 24)
      - Folder 7, 1965; 3 items (Box 24)
    - Principles of Human Genetics - Chapter 29, 1954-1970; 2 folders (Box 24)
      - Folder 1, 1968; 1 item (Box 24)
      - Folder 2, 1954-1970; 8 items (Box 24)
    - Principles of Human Genetics - Chapter 30, 1961-1971; 3 folders (Box 24)
      - Folder 1, 1964-1971; 6 items (Box 24)
      - Folder 2, 1961-1965; 4 items (Box 24)
      - Folder 3, 1965-1971; 4 items (Box 24)
    - Principles of Human Genetics - Chapter 31, 1949-1970; 4 folders (Box 24)
      - Folder 1, 1965-1969; 3 items (Box 24)
      - Folder 2, 1965-1969; 3 items (Box 24)
      - Folder 3, 1949-1970; 5 items (Box 24)
      - Folder 4, 1965-1970; 9 items (Box 24)
    - Principles of Human Genetics - Chapter 32, 1962-1965; 4 items (Box 24)
    - Principles of Human Genetics - Corrections, 1960-1973; 9 folders (Box 24)
      - Folder 1, 1965 (ca); 1 item (Box 24)
      - Folder 2, 1960; 2 items (Box 24)
      - Folder 3, 1965 (ca); 1 item (Box 24)
      - Folder 4, 1961-1971; 8 items (Box 24)
      - Folder 5, 1965 (ca); 2 items (Box 24)
      - Folder 6, 1965 (ca); 1 item (Box 24)
      - Folder 7, 1973-1974; 5 items (Box 24)
      - Folder 8, 1973; 1 item (Box 24)
      - Folder 9, 1973; 1 item (Box 24)
    - Principles of Human Genetics - German edition, 1960-1967; 4 folders (Box 25)
      - Folder 1, 1960-1967; 14 items (Box 25)
      - Folder 2, 1967; 7 items (Box 25)
      - Folder 3, n.d.; 1 item (Box 25)
      - Folder 4, 1965; 9 items (Box 25)
    - Principles of Human Genetics - Publication Agreement, 1948; 1 item (Box 25)
    - Principles of Human Genetics - Reviews (1st Edition), 1942-1953; 11 folders (Box 25)
      - Folder 1, 1949-1950; 14 items (Box 25)
      - Folder 2, 1942-1950; 21 items (Box 25)
      - Folder 3, 1950-1951; 16 items (Box 25)
      - Folder 4, 1949-1950; 30 items (Box 25)
      - Folder 5, 1949-1950; 29 items (Box 25)
      - Folder 6, 1949-1950; 19 items (Box 25)
      - Folder 7, 1949-1950; 26 items (Box 25)
      - Folder 8, 1949-1950; 13 items (Box 25)
      - Folder 9, 1950 (ca); 2 items (Box 25)
      - Folder 10, 1950-1951; 11 items (Box 25)
      - Folder 11, 1949-1953; 10 items (Box 25)
    - Principles of Human Genetics - Reviews and Comments, 1952-1962; 2 items (Box 25)
    - Principles of Human Genetics - Reviews (German edition), 1955-1957; 22 items (Box 25)
    - Principles of Human Genetics - Sales Figures, 1950-74, 1949-1973; 4 items (Box 25)
    - Principles of Human Genetics - Translations, 1957-1959; 14 items (Box 25)
  - Pritchard, R. H., 1959; 3 items (Box 25)
  - Professional Examination Service, 1966; 3 items (Box 25)
  - Progress in Atomic Medicine, 1963-1965; 4 items (Box 25)
  - Prokofieva-Belgovskaya, A., 1962-1970; 5 items (Box 25)
  - Provine, William B., 1971; 2 items (Box 25)
  - Przibram, Hans, 1928; 2 items (Box 25)
  - Puck, Theodore T., 1966-1970; 3 items (Box 25)
  - Punnett, R. C., 1938-1961; 8 items (Box 25)
  - Purdue University. Department of Biological Sciences, Research Activities of Senior Staff, 1963; 1 item (Box 25)
  - Pure Blood Society, 1967; 1 item (Box 25)
  - Puri, Prem S., 1966; 1 item (Box 25)
  - Puttanna, C. R., 1961-1966; 18 items (Box 25)
  - Queen, Frank B., 1951; 1 item (Box 25)
  - Quick, Armand J., 1969; 1 item (Box 25)
  - Quintanilha, A., 1931-1939; 4 items (Box 25)
  - Raacke, I. D., 1969; 3 items (Box 25)
  - Race, R. R., 1956-1968; 6 items (Box 25)
  - Race and racial prejudice, 1966-1975; 18 items (Box 25)
  - Radiation Machinery Corp., 1968; 1 item (Box 25)
  - Radiation Research Society, 1953; 1 item (Box 25)
  - Rafinesque, Constantin S., n.d.; 1 item (Box 25)
  - Raglan, Lord, 1960; 1 item (Box 25)
  - Rahn, Hermann, 1939-1968; 3 items (Box 25)
  - Rainer, John D., 1970; 2 items (Box 25)
  - Rajasekhara, K., 1968; 2 items (Box 25)
  - Ramamurthy, G., 1971-1975; 9 items (Box 25)
  - Ramot, B., 1972-1973; 3 items (Box 25)
  - Ramsey, Marry Jo, 1970; 2 items (Box 25)
  - Ramsey, Paul, 1965; 2 items (Box 25)
  - Rankin, John S., 1975; 1 item (Box 25)
  - Ranzi, Silvia, 1946; 1 item (Box 26)
  - Ranzoni, Frances V., 1947; 1 item (Box 26)
  - Rao, Debeeru Chandrasekhara, 1969-1970; 10 items (Box 26)
  - Rao, T. K., 1971; 4 items (Box 26)
  - Rapaport, Elliot, 1966-1967; 3 items (Box 26)
  - Rapoport, I. A., 1965; 1 item (Box 26)
  - Ratner, V. A., 1967; 1 item (Box 26)
  - Ratty, Frank, 1969; 1 item (Box 26)
  - Raven, Chr. P., 1965; 3 items (Box 26)
  - Ray, James D., 1969; 2 items (Box 26)
  - Razavi, Lawrence M., 1970; 4 items (Box 26)
  - Reddi, O. S., 1967-1968; 2 items (Box 26)
  - Redei, G. P., 1971; 3 items (Box 26)
  - Reed, Sheldon C., 1947-1972; 12 items (Box 26)
  - Reed, T. Edward, 1950-1973; 24 items (Box 26)
    Haldane, John Burdon Sanderson; Human genetics -- Race; Political issues -- Shockley, William; Population genetics; Publication; Teaching; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements
  - Reed, William B., 1964; 3 items (Box 26)
  - Reifenstein, George H., 1964; 2 items (Box 26)
  - Reitz, L. P., 1952; 1 item (Box 26)
  - Remondini, David J., 1970-1971; 3 items (Box 26)
  - Rendel, J. M., 1967; 1 item (Box 26)
  - Renkonen, K. O., 1967-1968; 6 items (Box 26)
  - Resseque, Patricia, 1968; 2 items (Box 26)
  - Reynolds, Mrs. Hugh E., 1926-1966; 10 items (Box 26)
  - Rhoads, Marcus, 1935; 1 item (Box 26)
  - Ribicoff, Abraham, 1956; 1 item (Box 26)
  - Richards, A., 1933-1935; 8 items (Box 26)
  - Richards, A. Glenn, Jr., 1936-1964; 3 items (Box 26)
  - Richardson, Alice, 1972; 2 items (Box 26)
  - Richardson, L. J., 1954; 1 item (Box 26)
  - Richner, Eugene, 1939; 1 item (Box 26)
  - Richter, Melissa L., 1960; 2 items (Box 26)
  - Rife, David C., 1955; 3 items (Box 26)
  - Riley, E. F., 1964; 2 items (Box 26)
  - Rimland, Bernard, 1967; 6 items (Box 26)
  - Rinaldi, Robert A., 1974; 1 item (Box 26)
  - Ripley, S. Dillon, 1965; 2 items (Box 26)
  - Ris, Hans, 1944; 1 item (Box 26)
  - Ritossa, Ferruccio, 1971; 10 items (Box 26)
  - Ritter, Hans, 1968-1969; 10 items (Box 26)
  - Roberts, J. A. Fraser, 1958-1973; 9 items (Box 26)
  - Roberts, Paul A., 1967; 2 items (Box 26)
  - Rochester Association of Scientists, 1946-1947; 17 items (Box 26)
    Atomic Energy Commission; Lectures, public speaking; Political issues; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.
  - Rockefeller Foundation, 1929-1971; 7 folders (Box 26)
    Baker, Gladys E.; Bodenstein, Dietrich; Committee activities -- Radiation effects; Constantinescu, G. K.; Displaced German scholars -- Holtfreter, Johannes; Drosophila genetics; Fellowships, assistantships -- Ephrussi, Boris; Fellowships, assistantships -- Stern, Curt; Hanson, Frank Blair; Human genetics; Kodani, Masuo; National Academy of Sciences; Political issues -- Anti-Semitism; Population genetics -- Tsubaki, Koji; Radiation genetics; Radiophosphorus; Recommendations -- Bishop, Sherman C.; Recommendations -- Goldschmidt, Richard Benedict; Recommendations -- Hadorn, Ernst; Recommendations -- Spencer, Warren P.; Referee's report -- Snell, George D.; Research support -- Heidenthal, Gertrude; Rockefeller Foundation; Schaeffer, Elizabeth; Stalker, Harrison Dailey; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements; University of California, Berkeley; University of Rochester -- Steward, Frederick Campion; Weaver, Warren; World War II -- Frisch, Karl von
    - Folder 1, 1929-1935; 21 items (Box 26)
    - Folder 2, 1935-1938; 20 items (Box 26)
    - Folder 3, 1938-1945; 23 items (Box 26)
    - Folder 4, 1940-1944; 27 items (Box 26)
    - Folder 5, 1944-1947; 40 items (Box 26)
    - Folder 6, 1947-1961; 17 items (Box 26)
    - Folder 7, 1950-1971; 22 items (Box 26)
  - Rockefeller Foundation. Grant Reports, 1932-1933; 5 items (Box 26)
  - Roderick, Thomas H., 1966-1972; 8 items (Box 26)
  - Roman, Herschel L., 1951-1968; 4 items (Box 26)
  - Ronald Press Co., 1957-1969; 5 items (Box 26)
  - Roper, J. Alan, 1967-1968; 4 items (Box 26)
  - Rose, Stanley, 1969; 2 items (Box 26)
  - Rosen, David, 1966; 3 items (Box 26)
  - Rosen, Saul W., 1965; 2 items (Box 26)
  - Rosenberg, Leon E., 1970; 1 item (Box 26)
  - Rosenberg, M., 1938; 1 item (Box 26)
  - Rosenberg, Marie, ? items (Box 26)
  - Rosenberg, Michael W., 1969; 2 items (Box 26)
  - Rosenberg, Otto, 1927; 1 item (Box 26)
  - Rosenow, George, 1964-1969; 2 items (Box 26)
  - Rosenthal, Jerry, 1969; 2 items (Box 26)
  - Rosenthal, Naomi, 1969-1971; 7 items (Box 26)
  - Rosland, Jean, 1951; 3 items (Box 26)
  - Rostaud, Jean, 1930; 5 items (Box 26)
  - Roth, Leonard, 1968; 6 items (Box 26)
  - Rothschild, Lord, 1959; 6 items (Box 26)
  - Rothstein, Philip, 1965; 2 items (Box 26)
  - Rotkin, I. D., 1964; 1 item (Box 26)
  - Rowan, Joan, 1971; 1 item (Box 26)
  - Rucki, Tadeusz, 1963-1965; 3 items (Box 26)
  - Rudd, Noreen L., 1970; 2 items (Box 26)
  - Ruddle, Frank H., 1966-1973; 7 items (Box 26)
  - Rüdiger, W., 1972; 6 items (Box 26)
  - Rüdin, E., 1956; 1 item (Box 26)
  - Rudkin, George T., 1971; 3 items (Box 26)
  - Rudorf, Wilhelm, 1954; 2 items (Box 26)
  - Rugh, Roberts, 1968; 2 items (Box 27)
  - Runnström, John, 1932-1969; 5 items (Box 27)
  - Russell, Elizabeth S., 1966-1968; 6 items (Box 27)
  - Russell, Liane Brauch, 1965; 2 items (Box 27)
  - Russell, M. A., 1963; 3 items (Box 27)
  - Russell, William L., 1959-1965; 3 items (Box 27)
  - Rust, Eric C., n.d.; 1 item (Box 27)
  - Rust, Thomas, 1970; 2 items (Box 27)
  - Sagan, Lynn, 1964-1965; 2 items (Box 27)
  - St. Mary's Hospital, San Francisco, 1965; 2 items (Box 27)
  - Salzano, Francisco M., 1974; 2 items (Box 27)
  - Sang, J. H., 1964; 1 item (Box 27)
  - Sanghvi, L. D., 1962; 8 items (Box 27)
  - Sarkar, Mridula, 1969; 3 items (Box 27)
  - Sarkar, S. S., 1964-1969; 21 items (Box 27)
    Human genetics; Publication
  - Sato, T., 1938; 1 item (Box 27)
  - Saturday Evening Post. "Adventures of the Mind" (series), 1959-1960; 6 items (Box 27)
    Eugenics; Human genetics; Invitations; Publication -- Saturday Evening Post
  - Saunders and Co., 1939; 2 items (Box 27)
  - W. B. Saunders Co. (Publishers), 1943-1944; 2 items (Box 27)
  - Sax, Karl, 1934-1947; 4 items (Box 27)
  - Schaefer, Ann, 1966-1967; 11 items (Box 27)
    Human genetics -- Africa; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.
  - Schaefer, M., 1932; 1 item (Box 27)
  - Schaefer, Stanley, 1968; 1 item (Box 27)
  - Schafer, Brenhilda, 1963; 2 items (Box 27)
  - Scharrer, Berta, 1969; 2 items (Box 27)
  - Schaxel, Julius, 1935; 4 items (Box 27)
  - Scheinberg, I. Herbert, 1964; 2 items (Box 27)
  - Scheinfeld, Amram, 1951-1968; 7 items (Box 27)
  - Schiller, Alfred, 1967; 3 items (Box 27)
  - Schlachter, Max, 1967; 1 item (Box 27)
  - Schluter, Mrs., 1965-1966; 5 items (Box 27)
  - Schmidt, G. A., 1960-1967; 6 items (Box 27)
  - Schnee, L., 1941; 1 item (Box 27)
  - Schneiderman, Howard A., 1967-1970; 3 items (Box 27)
  - Schoenheimer, Salome, 1947; 2 items (Box 27)
  - Schofield, John T., 1970; 2 items (Box 27)
  - Schotte, Oscar E., 1941; 2 items (Box 27)
  - Schrader, Franz, 1926-1961; 3 folders (Box 27)
    Bauer, Hans; Biographical and personal data -- Anderson, Ernest Gustav; Biographical and personal data -- Belar, Karl; Biographical and personal data -- Calkins, Gary Nathan; Biographical and personal data -- Dunn, Leslie Clarence; Biographical and personal data -- Goldschmidt, Richard Benedict; Biographical and personal data -- Hecht, Selig; Biographical and personal data -- Heilbrunn, Lewis Victor; Biographical and personal data -- Huettner, Alfred F.; Biographical and personal data -- Just, Gunther; Biographical and personal data -- Morgan, Thomas Hunt; Biographical and personal data -- Muller, Hermann Joseph; Biographical and personal data -- Schultz, Jack; Biographical and personal data -- Sturtevant, Alfred Henry; Biographical and personal data -- Wilson, Edmund Beecher; California Institute of Technology; Carothers, Estrella Eleanor; Columbia University; Cooper, Kenneth Willard; Cytogenetics; Darlington, Cyril Dean; Dobzhansky, Theodosius; Ephrussi, Boris; McClintock, Barbara; McClung, Clarence Erwin; Pollister, Arthur W.; Publication; Ris, Hans; World War II -- Impact on science; Zoology
    - Folder 1, 1926-1931; 12 items (Box 27)
    - Folder 2, 1933-1946; 34 items (Box 27)
    - Folder 3, 1949-1961; 11 items (Box 27)
  - Schrader, Sally Hughes, 1927-1973; 11 items (Box 27)
    Biographical and personal data -- Schrader, Franz; Conferences and symposia; Congratulations, greetings, thanks; Cytogenetics; Evolution; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements
  - Schreider, E., 1967; 2 items (Box 27)
  - Schrödinger, Erwin, 1934; 2 items (Box 27)
  - Schubert, Dr. von, 1931; 1 item (Box 27)
  - Schubinger, G., 1968; 2 items (Box 27)
  - Schuler, Frederic, 1965; 2 items (Box 27)
  - Schull, William J., 1962-1970; 4 items (Box 27)
  - Schultz, Helen Redfield, 1927-1971; 7 items (Box 27)
  - Schultz, Jack, 1927-1968; 2 folders (Box 27)
    Belar, Karl; Biographical and personal data; Bridges, Calvin B.; California Institute of Technology; Columbia University; Cytogenetics; Dobzhansky, Theodosius; Drosophila genetics; Goldschmidt, Richard Benedict; Jollos, Victor; Kiefer, Barry I.; Muller, Hermann Joseph; Publication; Referee's report -- Alava, Aloha Margaret Hannah
    - Folder 1, 1927-1931; 8 items (Box 27)
    - Folder 2, 1939-1968; 7 items (Box 27)
  - Schultz, Walter, 1931; 1 item (Box 27)
  - Schuster, Sister M. Helen, 1969; 2 items (Box 27)
  - Schwemmle, Julius, 1930-1947; 4 items (Box 27)
  - Science (Journal), 1937-1972; 27 items (Box 27)
    Boveri, Theodor; Evolution; Publication -- Science; Referee's report -- Ehrman, Lee Rothschild; Referee's report -- Fox, Arthur L.; Referee's report -- Kazazian, Haig H., Jr.; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.; World War II -- Impact on science
  - The Science of Genetics (Film). Critique, 1962-1963; 2 items (29 pages) (Box 27)
    California State Department of Education; Reviews -- The Science of Genetics (film)
  - Science Journal, 1969; 1 item (Box 27)
  - Scientific American (Journal), 1967; 1 item (Box 27)
  - Scientific Monthly, 1943-1944; 22 items (Box 27)
    Editorial matters -- Scientific Monthly; Publication -- Scientific Monthly
  - Scientists' Committee on Loyalty Problems, 1946-1950; 8 folders (Box 27)
    Atomic Energy Commission; Committee activities -- Minutes; Federation of American Scientists -- Scientists' Committee on Loyalty Problems; National Science Foundation; Political issues -- Loyalty oaths; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.
    - Folder 1, 1948-1956; 5 items (Box 27)
    - Folder 2, 1950; 5 items (Box 27)
    - Folder 3, 1947-1950; 14 items (Box 27)
    - Folder 4, 1947-1950; 11 items (Box 27)
    - Folder 5, 1948-1949; 13 items (Box 27)
    - Folder 6, 1948-1949; 4 items (Box 27)
    - Folder 7, 1949; 8 items (Box 27)
    - Folder 8, 1946-1949; 8 items (Box 27)
  - Scremin, L., 1960; 1 item (Box 28)
  - Scriver, Charles R. "Problem of signal-to-noise ratio in screening", n.d.; 1 item (Box 28)
  - Seaborg, Glenn T., 1958-1967; 3 items (Box 28)
  - Seecof, Robert, 1968; 5 items (Box 28)
  - Seidel, Friedrich, 1927-1931; 3 items (Box 28)
  - Seif, Leonhard, 1947; 2 items (Box 28)
  - Seiler, Mrs. F. H., 1960-1961; 2 items (Box 28)
  - Seiler, Jakob, 1929-1970; 11 items (Box 28)
    Genetics -- Lymantria; Genetics -- Solenobia; Goldschmidt, Richard Benedict
  - Seitz, Frederick, 1968; 1 item (Box 28)
  - Sekiguti, K., 1931; 1 item (Box 28)
  - Sekla, B. (Bohumil), 1961-1967; 16 items (Box 28)
    Genetics -- Czechoslovakia; Honors -- Mendel Medal; International Congress of Human Genetics -- Third Congress; Mendel, Gregor; Nemec, Bohumil; Publication
  - Sen, S. K., 1972; 2 items (Box 28)
  - Serban, Mihai, 1967; 3 items (Box 28)
  - Severinghaus, Aura Edward, 1959; 2 items (Box 28)
  - Shahnawaz, Mehebook, 1974; 1 item (Box 28)
  - Sharma, A. K., 1963; 1 item (Box 28)
  - Shaw, Dick, n.d.; 3 items (Box 28)
  - Shaw, Edward B., 1970; 1 item (Box 28)
  - Shaw, Margery W., 1964-1971; 5 items (Box 28)
  - Shaw, Richard F., 1967; 2 items (Box 28)
  - Shaw, Russell F., 1964; 1 item (Box 28)
  - Sheer, Denise, 1975; 1 item (Box 28)
  - Sheline, Raymond, 1948; 2 items (Box 28)
  - Shell Development Research Club, 1947-1959; 2 items (Box 28)
  - Shen, Tun Hui, 1932; 1 item (Box 28)
  - Sherwood, Eva, 1958-1962; 2 items (Box 28)
  - Sherwood, Eva and Curt Stern. Chromosome IV and sex balance in Drosophila melanogaster, 5 folders (Box 28)
    Drosophila genetics; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.
    - Folder 1, n.d.; 1 item (Box 28)
    - Folder 2, n.d.; 1 item (Box 28)
    - Folder 3, n.d.; 1 item (Box 28)
    - Folder 4, n.d.; 1 item (Box 28)
    - Folder 5, n.d.; 1 item (Box 28)
  - Shettles, Landrum B., 1960-1970; 3 items (Box 28)
  - Shockley, William, 1965-1973; 8 items (Box 28)
    Human genetics -- Race; National Academy of Sciences; Referee's report
  - Shotwell, James T., 1947; 1 item (Box 28)
  - Shreffler, Donald C., 1971-1972; 3 items (Box 28)
  - Shull, A. Franklin, 1948; 1 item (Box 28)
  - Shull, George Harrison, 1937-1952; 45 items (Box 28)
    Business -- Genetics; Editorial matters -- Genetics; Garrod, Archibald Edward, Sir; Genetics Society of America -- Golden Jubilee; History of biology, especially genetics; Human genetics -- Nomenclature; Publication -- Genetics; Referee's report -- Dubinin, Nikolai Petrovich; Requests for reprints; Tschermak-Seysenegg, Erich von; World War II -- Impact on science
  - Siemans, George J., 1968; 2 items (Box 28)
  - Sigerist, H. E., 1944; 2 items (Box 28)
  - Silber, Frederick, 1969; 2 items (Box 28)
  - Silow, R. A., 1944-1947; 2 items (Box 28)
  - Simpósio Internacional De Genetica (São Paulo, Brazil, 1966), 1965; 2 items (Box 28)
  - Simpson, George Gaylord, 1946-1947; 7 items (Box 28)
  - Sinclair, John, 1957; 1 item (Box 28)
  - Singh, Jai Rup, 1970; 4 items (Box 28)
  - Singleton, Ralph W., 1955-1968; 10 items (Box 28)
  - Siniscalco, M., 1965; 2 items (Box 28)
  - Sinotocirc, Yosito, 1953-1954; 2 items (Box 28)
  - Sirks, M. J., 1929-1932; 2 items (Box 28)
  - Skalinska, Maria, 1958; 1 item (Box 28)
  - Skoog, E. N., 1942; 3 items (Box 28)
  - Skowron, Stanislaw, 1928-1968; 12 items (Box 28)
  - Slater, Eliot, 1964; 1 item (Box 28)
  - Slatis, Herman B., 1964-1970; 8 items (Box 28)
  - Slepkow, W., 1929; 3 items (Box 28)
  - Slifer, Eleanor H., 1940-1941; 16 items (Box 28)
  - Sloan-Kettering Institute, 1964-1965; 2 items (Box 28)
  - Smith, John Maynard, 1962; 2 items (Box 28)
  - Smith, M. Brewster, 1967; 1 item (Box 28)
  - Smith, P. Dennis, 1968; 3 items (Box 28)
  - Smith, Ralph I., 1967-1968; 4 items (Box 28)
  - Smith, Susan M., 1971-1972; 2 items (Box 28)
  - Smith, Wilbur M., 1957; 3 items (Box 28)
  - Smithies, Oliver, 1964-1971; 3 items (Box 28)
  - Smithies, O. "Chromosomal rearrangements and protein structure", 1964 (ca); 1 item (Box 28)
  - Smyth, Francis S., 1961-1964; 10 items (Box 28)
  - Snyder, Lawrence H., 1944-1953; 5 items (Box 28)
  - Sobels, F. H., 1968-1973; 3 items (Box 28)
  - Social Restoration Research Center, 1966; 3 items (Box 28)
  - Society for Developmental Biology, 1965; 4 items (Box 28)
  - Society for the Protection of Science and Learning, 1958; 2 items (Box 28)
  - Society for the Study of Development and Growth, 1946; 1 item (Box 28)
  - Society for the Study of Evolution, 1946; 9 items (Box 28)
  - Sokolow, T., 1930; 1 item (Box 28)
  - Solomon, Irene, 1964; 2 items (Box 28)
  - Sommerfield, Evelyn (Box 28)
    -see: Stern, Evelyn
  - Sondhi, K. C., 1960-1964; 14 items (Box 28)
  - Sonneborn, Tracy M., 1940-1970; 11 items (Box 28)
  - Spemann, Hans, 1931-1935; 3 items (Box 28)
  - Spencer, Warren P., 1929-1970; 18 items (Box 28)
    Biographical and personal data; Charles, Donald Randolph; Drosophila genetics; Fellowships, assistantships; Muller, Hermann Joseph; Publication; Radiation genetics; Recommendations -- Stalker, Harrison Dailey; Teaching -- Wooster College; University of California, Berkeley; University of Rochester; World War II -- Manhattan Project
  - Spiegelman, S., 1946; 1 item (Box 28)
  - Spielman, Richard, 1969; 2 items (Box 28)
  - Spiess, Eliot, 1961-1964; 3 items (Box 29)
  - Spitzer, Ralph, 1964; 3 items (Box 29)
  - Spivack, Morris J. "The Genesis of Cancer", 1950; 1 item (Box 29)
  - Spoehr, H. A., 1944; 2 items (Box 29)